# YUQIAN HUO

 $(314)\cdot 685\cdot 9048 \diamond$ huoyuqian@wustl.edu 1325 Boland Pl, Apt 2030  $\diamond$  St. Louis, MO 63117

#### **PROFILE**

I am a dedicated graduate Computer Science student interested in software security and system security. I have mastered C/C++ and am familiar with shell scripts, makefile, llvm and assembly languages. I have multiple experiences on security, cyber-physical systems, software development and IoT. Fluent in English and native in Chinese. Standardized tests: TOEFL 102, GRE 324.

#### **EDUCATION**

Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO

01.2020 - (Expected)12.2021

McKelvey School of Engineering

Major: Computer Science Degree: Master of Science

**GPA:** 3.8

Core courses: Object-Oriented Software Development Laboratory, Operating Systems Organization, Introduction to Computer Security, Recent Advances in Computer Security and Privacy

Southeast University Chengxian College, Nanjing, China

08.2015 - 06.2019

School of Electronic and Computer Science

Major: Electronic and Information Engineering Degree: Bachelor of Engineering

**GPA:** 3.78 Rank: 2/83

Core courses: Fundamentals of Computer and C program Design Theory, Fundamentals of Software Tech-

nology, Comprehensive Programming Design

#### PUBLICATION & PATENT

Jingyi Xie, Yuqian Huo, "Design and Improvement of a New Smart Cleaning Robot", *Electronic Test*, Vol.11, pp. 27-29, 140, June 2018.

A Smart Cleaning Robot, Patent no. 201820713157.2

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant 07.2021 - Present

Washington University in St. Louis, Computer Security & Privacy Laboratory

St. Louis, MO

- · Measured the number of indirect jumps, returns, write instructions and read instructions in those applications
- · Applied Clang CFI on those applications to measure the runtime overhead.
- · Utilized SVF to construct the points-to analysis of applications on real-time operating systems.
- · Currently working on applying CFI mechanisms on real-time operating systems using binary instrumentation.

Research Assistant 08.2018 - 01.2019

Southeast University, State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics

Nanjing, China

- · Conducted communications routinely with doctors in Gulou Hospital to acquire information about project requirement, especially details on software functional requirements.
- · Implemented C++ on Visual Studio to build MFC graphic user interface for the team to visualize B-scan results.
- · Helped the team debug using Caffe deep learning framework and Faster-RCNN algorithm to automatically recognize various fetal organs.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Computer Science Assistant

01.2021 - Present

Washington University in St. Louis

St. Louis. MO

- · Assisted professor holding studio sessions for object-oriented programming using C++.
- · Assisted professor as a grader and held Office Hours weekly.

#### **PROJECT**

### Design of Chess Games and Linux Filesystem

01.2020 - 05.2020

https://github.com/clairehyq/linux-fsystem

St. Louis, MO

- · Designed a C++ program with which you can play TicTacToe or Gomoku chess game.
- · Utilized OOP feature to realize to let user to choose either to play TicTacToe or Gomoku, to show the chess board after each turn, and to output the game results.
- · Used C++ to build a software simulation of a file system to realize linux-like command, such as ls, cp, rm, touch, cat, display, rename, grep and chmod.

# Design and Improvement of a Smart Cleaning Robot

04.2017 - 05.2018

Project Leader

Nanjing, China

- · Wrote programs with C Language and took advantages of PWM wave to control the motion directions and the speed of the drive.
- · Made the robot shell by 3D printing and assemble the rotating brushes.
- · Programmed ultrasonic and infrared rays sensor to detect the obstacles to respond promptly, and enhance the accuracy.
- · Added a relay to connect the module of sound control with the drive and realized the function of voice control and man-machine interaction.

# Design of a Digital Breath Alcohol Tester using MSP430F149

 $08.2017 \hbox{-} 09.2017$ 

Project Leader

Nanjing, China

- · Wrote the A/D conversion program of the alcohol sensor to transform the analog value to digital value.
- · Facilitated the display program of the 12864 LCD monitor and the control program of three indicator lights and buzzer on the package.
- · Modified the alcohol concentration program and alcohol sensor to enhance the accuracy of the tester according to data on the website of China General Administration of Quality Supervision, Inspection and Quarantine.

# HONORS AWARDS

Excellent Graduates at Southeast University Chengxian College	06.2019
Outstanding Student for Innovation Practice at Southeast University Chengxian College	05.2019
First Prize for Comprehensive Scholarship at Southeast University	
Chengxian College, won three times	10.2016 - 10.2018
Award for Academic Excellence at Southeast University Chengxian College	10.2017
First Prize, "Internet+" College Students Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition	
at Southeast University Chengxian College	09.2017

## SKILLS

Computer Languages C/C++, Intel and ARM Assembly Language, Java, Python, MATLAB

Databases MySQL

Tools Git, Vim, Bash Shell, Makefile, SVF, Ghidra, angr, AWS

Compiler Clang, LLVM, GCC